export const data=[
{
    question:"If the base sequence in DNA is 5' AAAT 3' then the base sequence in mRNA is",
    option1:"3'UUUU5'",
    option2:"5'AAAU3'",
    option3:"3'AAAU5'",
    option4:"5'UUUU3'",
    ans:2,
},
{

question:"Avery, MacLeod and Mc Carty used the S and R strains of streptococcus pneumoniae. They isolated and purified protein, DNA, RNA from the bacteria and treated them with related enzymes. They concluded that ",

option1:"DNA was transforming agent",
option2:"RNA was transforming agent",
option3:"Protein was transforming agent",
option4:"All are correct",
ans:1,
},
{
    question:"Identify the characteristic which is not applicable to the genetic code",
    option1:"Non-Polar",
    option2:"Non-Overlapping",
    option3:"Commaless",
    option4:"universal",
    ans:1,

},
{
    question:"Ribose is differentiable from deoxyribose in having ",
    option1:"Two extra oxygen",
    option2:"No oxygen",
    option3:"Hydroxyl group at 2nd carbon",
    option4:"universalOne extra hydrogen",
    ans:3,

},
{
    question:"A DNA strand is directly involved in the synthesis of all the following except ",
    option1:"Another DNA",
    option2:"t-RNA & m-RNA",
    option3:"r-RNA",
    option4:"Protein",
    ans:4,

},
{
    question:"The genes are responsible for growth and differentiation in an organism through regulation of  ",
    option1:"Translocation",
    option2:"Transformation",
    option3:"Transduction and translation",
    option4:"Translation and transcription",
    ans:4,

},
{
    question:"Genetic information is carried out by long chain molecule made up of  ",
    option1:"Amino acids",
    option2:"Enzymes",
    option3:"Nucleotides",
    option4:"Histone proteins",
    ans:3,

},
{
    question:"Anticodons are found in  ",
    option1:"mRNA",
    option2:"tRNA",
    option3:"rRNA",
    option4:"In all",
    ans:2,

},
{
    question:"Which of the following element is not found in nitrogenous base  ",
    option1:"Nitrogen",
    option2:"Hydrogen",
    option3:"Carbon",
    option4:"Phosphorus",
    ans:4,

},
{
    question:"Transfer of genetic information from a polymer of nucleotides to a polymer of amino acids is ",
    option1:"Replication",
    option2:"Transcription",
    option3:"Translation",
    option4:"Reverse transcription",
    ans:3,

},






];